<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🎒 mindset on lean learning</title>
    <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🎒 mindset on lean learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>the perfect neurochemical cocktail</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/10_neurochemical_cocktail.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/10_neurochemical_cocktail.html</guid>
      <description>Learning happens in a state of focus and being comfortable with frustration. This duo triggers the neurochemical cocktail needed for learning which consists of Acetylcholine, Epinephrine and Dopamine.&#xA;Focusing means paying attention and being alert at the same time. Paying attention releases Acetylcholine which helps with your focus. Being alert, on the other hand, releases Epinephrine which reduces anxiety and gives you the energy to learn.&#xA;To support your focus and the release of Acetylcholine, define what you want to learn and why you want to learn it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>methods to improve focus - time-based technique</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/20_focus_time_methods.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/20_focus_time_methods.html</guid>
      <description>Besides embracing frustration, the other important part of learning is focusing. But our focus can be fragile and we can get easily distracted. Be it through external things like our phones or internal events like thoughts and feelings.&#xA;Additionally, our focus depends on many variables. It depends on how we sleep at night, the time of day, what we eat, our emotional state, our stress level, our energy level, and so on.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>methods to improve focus - mind-based techniques</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/30_focus_mind_methods.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/30_focus_mind_methods.html</guid>
      <description>In addition to the time-based technique, there are also mind-based techniques to improve your focus. These can be used before and during learning.&#xA;2. dump vague thoughts One thing that can distract us the most are our own thoughts.&#xA;Vague thoughts seem to wait until we want to focus. And then, they start bubbling up. You want to focus but you start thinking about cleaning the kitchen. Or you remember that you wanted to call your parents.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>tldr: learning is supposed to be frustrating</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/40_tldr_learning_is_frustrating.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/40_tldr_learning_is_frustrating.html</guid>
      <description>The flow state is a place where things feel effortless. You know exactly what to do and you can do it. But learning doesn’t feel effortless. In fact it often isn&amp;rsquo;t. You have to explore, try to understand and rethink concepts all the time. And, most probably, you will make mistakes.&#xA;Learning is challenging. And sadly there is no hack.&#xA;So instead of flowing, learning feels frustrating.&#xA;But frustration has a bad reputation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>play as a portal to learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/50_play_as_protal_to_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/50_play_as_protal_to_learning.html</guid>
      <description>Most of us think of games when we hear playing. But playing is not just about games. Playing has important traits that can be used as a portal to learning. Playing helps you tap into focus and embrace frustration - two important learning components.&#xA;We played more when we were younger. We played and explored without overthinking. Everything was a huge experiment for us, and we tried, failed, and learned. But this changed while growing up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>the power of pause</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/60_power_of_pause.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 15:08:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/mindset/60_power_of_pause.html</guid>
      <description>Until now, we have emphasised the importance of focusing and embracing frustration. But learning has two stages. One of them is focus and frustration. The other one is rest. Resting is important for learning.&#xA;Learning is associated with changes in your brain. But the changes in your brain actually don&amp;rsquo;t happen while you are learning. They happen at rest.&#xA;The focus and frustration stage is just a highlighter. Neurotransmitters released during learning just highlight areas in your brain which are relevant to what you are learning.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
