<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🫶 introduction on lean learning</title>
    <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🫶 introduction on lean learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>why should I care?</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/10_why_should_i_care.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/10_why_should_i_care.html</guid>
      <description>Learning helps you expand your knowledge, follow your curiosities and adapt to new circumstances. But learning takes time and effort. During school and university, it was easier to learn. You had time. You had a curriculum to follow. You had deadlines for tests. Everything was prepared for you.&#xA;But it&amp;rsquo;s more difficult to learn while you are working.&#xA;You might want to learn about philosophy after work. You might want to improve your communication and writing skills.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>what is the LeLe method?</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/20_what_is_lele.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/20_what_is_lele.html</guid>
      <description>Learning can be annoying. It can get frustrating trying to understand a concept or there might be too many interesting topics to learn or you can even fall into the trap of shallow learning - keeping yourself entertained without actually learning anything.&#xA;To solve these problems, the LeLe method aims to make learning intentional, enjoyable and forgiving.&#xA;intentional It makes learning intentional so that you can find the time to learn and focus on what you want to learn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>inspiration for LeLe</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/30_inspiration_for_lele.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/introduction/30_inspiration_for_lele.html</guid>
      <description>The LeLe method is inspired by a variety of ideas and people from the space of productivity and neuroscience. LeLe tries to combine those diverse ideas into one coherent learning framework.&#xA;So, special thanks go out to Ryan Carroll and Bullet Journal Method, Andrew Hubermann and the Hubermann Lab Podcast, Justin Sung and his insights into learning and Ryan Singer and his Shape Up method.&#xA;The Bullet Journal Method inspired the LeLe method to be intentional and less distracting.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
