<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>🍱 place and planning on lean learning</title>
    <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 🍱 place and planning on lean learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>lama&#43;n: a place to learn</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/10_laman_place_to_learn.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/10_laman_place_to_learn.html</guid>
      <description>After going through the mindset for learning, it&amp;rsquo;s now time to talk about a place to learn. A place where you can collect materials, plan your learning and actually learn. It can be fun and adventurous to research and adjust your learning system. But it also bears a trap. A trap in which you never start learning but constantly look for a perfect system. Adjusting your learning system and searching for the perfect setup can get annoying and frustrating.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>take time for learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/20_take_time_for_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/20_take_time_for_learning.html</guid>
      <description>After having a place to learn, we now need to find the time to learn. But that&amp;rsquo;s the problem. Finding time doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. Instead of finding time, we have to take time to learn.&#xA;We may avoid learning by letting random tasks creep into our schedule. We might also hope that magically a time slot will appear in which we can learn. We don&amp;rsquo;t plan for it. We let it to chance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>how to plan your learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/30_how_to_plan_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/30_how_to_plan_learning.html</guid>
      <description>The problem with typical learning plans is that we often make a rigorous plan. We don&amp;rsquo;t define why we want to learn or what we want to learn and we don&amp;rsquo;t include any practice. This results in randomly learning a bit here and there, trying to transcribe and cram as much as possible instead of understanding it. This often leads to giving up on learning altogether.&#xA;But there might be an alternative to this standard way of planning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>scattered vs shaped learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/40_shaped_vs_scattered_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/place/40_shaped_vs_scattered_learning.html</guid>
      <description>Learning can take place in two ways - planned and random. Both are relevant and should be included in every learning journey. Planned learning, or as it is called in LeLe, shaped learning is about collecting materials and assembling them into a learning unit. You can even shape multiple learnings and intentionally decide what to focus on and what to ignore. This makes shaped learning very time-intensive and deliberate.&#xA;But learning can also happen randomly.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
