<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>📚 learning on lean learning</title>
    <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in 📚 learning on lean learning</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>the three learning phases</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/10_three_phases_of_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/10_three_phases_of_learning.html</guid>
      <description>Learning is more than just sitting down and starting to study. Learning has three phases that repeat themselves and can even intertwine. These three phases are priming, studying, and practising.&#xA;priming The goal of priming is to get an abstract idea about a topic. No details. You skim, explore and try to understand the connection of concepts inside your learning unit. You just worry about the big picture and ignore all the details.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>mind mapping</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/20_mind_mapping.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/20_mind_mapping.html</guid>
      <description>The main learning technique of LeLe is mind mapping. It is used in all three learning phases - priming, studying and even practising if you are trying to learn information. But how do we mind map?&#xA;define focus question Start your mind map by defining a focus question. A question you want to answer inside your mind map. Depending on your questions your mind map might look different. Additionally, a focus question can help you focus on something specific and avoid bigger detours into different areas and topics.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iterative learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/30_iterative_learning.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/30_iterative_learning.html</guid>
      <description>Learning is not about sitting down and studying once. Learning is not about understanding it perfectly immediately. Learning is about constant iteration. You build up your understanding step by step correcting your mistakes and misunderstandings along the way.&#xA;Iterative learning is powerful because learning itself is recursive and excursive. Recursive meaning: you have to rethink, re-understanding and re-practice to find gaps and questions in your understanding and correct them. Excursive because your learning journey is not the same as someone else&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>iterative mind mapping to overcome emotions</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/40_iterative_mapping_emotions.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/40_iterative_mapping_emotions.html</guid>
      <description>The iterative mind mapping technique is not only great because of its learning capabilities but also because of its beauty in dealing with emotions. It can help you overcome motivation, feeling overwhelmed and the fear of not getting it right.&#xA;no motivation There are times when you are motivated and can jump right into learning. But there are also times of no motivation. It is difficult to sit down and start learning if you have no motivation at all.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>prime by making a M.E.S.S.</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/50_priming_mess.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/50_priming_mess.html</guid>
      <description>The goal of priming is to get an abstract and rough idea about a topic or concept. A big picture overview. It has to be abstract. Ignore the details otherwise you will get lost in them.&#xA;The idea is to start thinking, start having questions and awaken your curiosity. The LeLe method allows you to prime by making a M.E.S.S. - map, explore, skim and self-explain.&#xA;map Map out your thoughts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S.I.M.P. method for learning</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/60_learning_simp.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/60_learning_simp.html</guid>
      <description>The next phase of learning, after priming and before practicing, is studying. For this we can use the S.I.M.P. method. This method also incorporates the iterative mapping approach from before.&#xA;The S.I.M.P. method stands for&#xA;self-explaining iterating mapping pausing and all of them should be used while studying.&#xA;self-explain Self-explain what you are trying to learn. Skim, read or watch the learning content. But rather than transcribing what you consume, explain it to yourself.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>practice makes perfect</title>
      <link>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/70_practice_perfect.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 12:17:22 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kmltkc.de/leanlearning/learning/70_practice_perfect.html</guid>
      <description>After priming and studying, the final phase of learning is practising. Through practice and repetition, we can internalise what we are learning and build expertise and knowledge. Practice makes perfect.&#xA;But how should we practice? It really depends on what you are trying to learn. Most of the time you will hear advice like &amp;ldquo;learn by building a project&amp;rdquo; which is good advice. The LeLe method recommends it too. But not everything we learn can be connected to a project.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
